Now another important thing for you to remember, and this is going to be a little difficult, because we all tend to like to please people, we all tend to like accolades and praise.
But it's very important that you remember everyone does not have to love your speech.
Everyone does not have to love you.
I found that out many, many years ago as a college professor when I used to try to please all of my students.
And invariably I would have one, or maybe two, a semester, that just, they just didn't like me.
It didn't matter what I did, they didn't like me.
And that was ok.
It's ok if one or two people disagree with your speech.
It's ok if one or two or three people don't like you.
You have to continue to allow that to be ok. You also have to take a look at past failures as a speaker.
Well, the last time I did that speech everybody hated it.
Or, everybody said I was bad.
Past failures of people not liking your speech, or not liking you, have nothing to do with present and future presentations.
Maybe that happened before.
Ok, so what?
Move on.
It won't happen this time just because it happened last time.